<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Art on Juliano Garcia</title>
    <link>https://robotenique.github.io/categories/art/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Art on Juliano Garcia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robotenique.github.io/categories/art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>From Classification to Chaos</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/from-classification-to-chaos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/from-classification-to-chaos/</guid>
      <description>Logistic Regression Logistic Differential Equation Logistic Map Bifurcation Diagram Chaos in Complex Space The Derivation The Mandelbrot Set Conclusion    Mathematics has an interesting property of connecting different fields through relatively simple transformations. Starting from logistic regression, I&amp;rsquo;ll explore what happens when we apply basic mathematical operations like discretization and complex plane extensions to its underlying function. By following these transformations, we end up visiting concepts from dynamical systems, chaos theory, and fractals - fields that might seem distant from the classification algorithms that we data scientists know so well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative art using Bézier Curves</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/bezier-curve-gen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/bezier-curve-gen/</guid>
      <description>Bézier Curves I recently started toying with Processing and generative art, and in this little journey I&amp;rsquo;ve come across a specific method for curve drawing called the Bézier Curve. It is a parametric curve that is widely used in computer graphics, almost everywhere you need to draw curves: digital typography, vector graphics, illustration software (Adobe Illustrator, Inkscape), animation, etc.
This curve has a very interesting mathematical definition (it also has a recursive definition) and can be defined for any degree n.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperreality meets Utopian Virtual</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/hyperreality-utopian-virtual/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/hyperreality-utopian-virtual/</guid>
      <description>More real than reality In postmodern semiotics Baudrillard coined the term hyperreality, basically a state/characteristic of something unable to be distinguished from reality. When thinking about the concept itself, it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to understand — in a semiotic sense — what Baudrillard defines as simulation and simulacra. To not delve deep into these subjects here (you can find more in this book), these concepts manifest themselves in postmodern societies with increasingly meta references, for everything.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>