<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Misc on Juliano Garcia</title>
    <link>https://robotenique.github.io/categories/misc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Misc on Juliano Garcia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robotenique.github.io/categories/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools for a more mindful Internet and Social Media experience</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/internet-mindful-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/internet-mindful-tools/</guid>
      <description>Intro What are the core values of how you use the internet?  Minimizing enshittification Minimizing signal-to-noise ratio   Vivaldi Browser Extensions  General Productivity related Social Media related   (extra) Mobile tools    Intro This quick blogpost wil be mostly a categorization for myself about some general tools I use to make social media and internet browsing more useful and a generally better experience (for me at least).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethically Aware Recommender Systems in Social Media</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/ethically-aware-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/ethically-aware-systems/</guid>
      <description>This post is based on an article I wrote some time ago; There may be some inconsistencies with the references, sorry.
Reccomender Systems In a world where digital information is increasing every year, recommender systems are very important tools to handle the challenge of information overload. A recommender system is a type of information filtering system with the ability to filter information from a large amount of data generated dynamically, according to a given preference, observed behavior or interest from the user [1].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atom &amp; Latex</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/2017-05-24-atom-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/2017-05-24-atom-latex/</guid>
      <description>LaTeX is a DSL (domain specific language) that provides powerful typesetting tools. You can write complex mathematical expressions and much more, for example, the following characteristic polynomial expression was rendered using LaTeX (MathJax):
$$ \chi(\lambda) = \left| \begin{array}{ccc} \lambda - a &amp;amp; -b &amp;amp; -c \\\
-d &amp;amp; \lambda - e &amp;amp; -f \\\
-g &amp;amp; -h &amp;amp; \lambda - i \end{array} \right| $$
There are amazing online software to work with LaTeX such as ShareLaTeX or Overleaf, but sometimes you don&amp;rsquo;t have access to the internet, or want to have a compact environment to do most of your job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atom editor</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/2017-03-21-atom-edit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/2017-03-21-atom-edit/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever heard of Atom? Atom is a text editor, similar to Sublime Text, but with a lot of different features, and much more flexibility and freedom. It&amp;rsquo;s described as A hackable text editor for the 21st century, because it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to create and change many of the settings available, and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot!
Atom is my personal editor, I prefer using it than the proprietary (but relatively good) Sublime Text, and other MAINSTREAM editors like vi/vim or emacs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>