<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computer Science on Juliano Garcia</title>
    <link>https://robotenique.github.io/categories/computer-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computer Science on Juliano Garcia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robotenique.github.io/categories/computer-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>From Classification to Chaos</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/from-classification-to-chaos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/from-classification-to-chaos/</guid>
      <description>Logistic Regression Logistic Differential Equation Logistic Map Bifurcation Diagram Chaos in Complex Space The Derivation The Mandelbrot Set Conclusion    Mathematics has an interesting property of connecting different fields through relatively simple transformations. Starting from logistic regression, I&amp;rsquo;ll explore what happens when we apply basic mathematical operations like discretization and complex plane extensions to its underlying function. By following these transformations, we end up visiting concepts from dynamical systems, chaos theory, and fractals - fields that might seem distant from the classification algorithms that we data scientists know so well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools for a more mindful Internet and Social Media experience</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/internet-mindful-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/internet-mindful-tools/</guid>
      <description>Intro What are the core values of how you use the internet?  Minimizing enshittification Minimizing signal-to-noise ratio   Vivaldi Browser Extensions  General Productivity related Social Media related   (extra) Mobile tools    Intro This quick blogpost wil be mostly a categorization for myself about some general tools I use to make social media and internet browsing more useful and a generally better experience (for me at least).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Histograms for efficient gradient boosting</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/gbm-histogram/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/gbm-histogram/</guid>
      <description>Gradient Boosting GBM or Gradient Boosting Machines are a form of machine learning algorithms based on additive models. The currently most widely known implementations of it are the XGBoost and LightGBM libraries, and they are common choices for modeling supervised learning problems based on structured data. Generally, the output model in boosting is created by iteratively building weak learners, where each new weak learner weights more the mispredictions of the last learner, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative art using Bézier Curves</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/bezier-curve-gen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/bezier-curve-gen/</guid>
      <description>Bézier Curves I recently started toying with Processing and generative art, and in this little journey I&amp;rsquo;ve come across a specific method for curve drawing called the Bézier Curve. It is a parametric curve that is widely used in computer graphics, almost everywhere you need to draw curves: digital typography, vector graphics, illustration software (Adobe Illustrator, Inkscape), animation, etc.
This curve has a very interesting mathematical definition (it also has a recursive definition) and can be defined for any degree n.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethically Aware Recommender Systems in Social Media</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/ethically-aware-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/ethically-aware-systems/</guid>
      <description>This post is based on an article I wrote some time ago; There may be some inconsistencies with the references, sorry.
Reccomender Systems In a world where digital information is increasing every year, recommender systems are very important tools to handle the challenge of information overload. A recommender system is a type of information filtering system with the ability to filter information from a large amount of data generated dynamically, according to a given preference, observed behavior or interest from the user [1].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating grid/image points in Python</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/2017-09-17-image-grid-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/2017-09-17-image-grid-python/</guid>
      <description>I was doing some assignment about the Percolation Problem, where given a graph, find if the top of the graph is connected to the bottom. There was some test files included, but I wanted to create my own images.
The input file of my assignment has, in the first line, the dimensions of the image. The images are always in a square ratio, n x n &amp;ldquo;pixels&amp;rdquo;. The remaining lines of the file contains pairs (a b) of the coordinates in the grid n x n.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug C programs using gdb</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/2017-03-12-debug-gdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/2017-03-12-debug-gdb/</guid>
      <description>GDB(GNU Project Debugger) is, as the name implies, a debugger with a lot of features to make your life easy when programming in C. Using gdb helps to debug C programs in real execution time, i.e. you can put break points in the program to evaluate the value of variables, detect when something has gone wrong, and many other uses. Here I&amp;rsquo;ll cover the basics that I use to debug simple C programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast and easy Python LAN server</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/2017-03-12-python-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/2017-03-12-python-server/</guid>
      <description>This is a very simple tip, but it&amp;rsquo;s very useful when you want others to access your files, or you want to transfer files easily. Just open the terminal, navigate to the folder you want to serve, and then type:
$ python -m SimpleHTTPServer The server will be created in the IP of your machine.
To find your IP, type
$ ifconfig -all or
$ ip a If you&amp;rsquo;re using Python 3.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>