<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Juliano Garcia</title>
    <link>https://robotenique.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Juliano Garcia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robotenique.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Python map</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/2017-03-10-python-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/2017-03-10-python-map/</guid>
      <description>A cool Subway map to know more about the different things you can do with Python!
by Hairy Sun - Geek blog!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethically Aware Recommender Systems in Social Media</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/ethically-aware-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/ethically-aware-systems/</guid>
      <description>This post is based on an article I wrote some time ago; There may be some inconsistencies with the references, sorry.
Reccomender Systems In a world where digital information is increasing every year, recommender systems are very important tools to handle the challenge of information overload. A recommender system is a type of information filtering system with the ability to filter information from a large amount of data generated dynamically, according to a given preference, observed behavior or interest from the user [1].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperreality meets Utopian Virtual</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/hyperreality-utopian-virtual/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/hyperreality-utopian-virtual/</guid>
      <description>More real than reality In postmodern semiotics Baudrillard coined the term hyperreality, basically a state/characteristic of something unable to be distinguished from reality. When thinking about the concept itself, it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to understand — in a semiotic sense — what Baudrillard defines as simulation and simulacra. To not delve deep into these subjects here (you can find more in this book), these concepts manifest themselves in postmodern societies with increasingly meta references, for everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving your statistical inferences</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/improving-your-statistical-inferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/improving-your-statistical-inferences/</guid>
      <description>Why study inferential statistics? It&amp;rsquo;s very common to read news and articles with &amp;ldquo;studies have shown that X!&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;science proves that Y&amp;rdquo; in today&amp;rsquo;s age of information. Or even read scientific papers with some dubious affirmations when dealing with reporting results and drawing conclusions from experimental data. Statistical inference is one of those topics in which the basic concepts are very important to grasp to avoid any misconceptions when interpreting it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monte Carlo simulation of a multi-spin roulette mechanic</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/fortune-cat-simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/fortune-cat-simulation/</guid>
      <description>Last year I found out about a Gacha game called Saint Seiya Awakening, which I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to play for some time, but then gave up on it. However I still do watch people play it, people who usually have enough time to invest in the game (it demands quite an amount of your time to be at a competitive level). Gacha games are usually free-to-play, but it is full of loot boxes, roulettes, slot machines, microtransactions and everything else that makes the player want to buy stuff in-game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I am Juliano Garcia, a Computer Scientist from IME-USP at the University of São Paulo, and this is my personal blog. In 2019 I graduated in Computer Science with an specialization in Artificial Intelligence, focusing my studies in statistics, algorithms, machine learning and related areas in AI such as game theory, classical planning, knowledge-based systems, etc.
I currently work as a Data Scientist using state-of-the-art data science to empower people in their finantial lives at Nubank&amp;rsquo;s Credit team, in São Paulo/Brazil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Study on Gradient Boosting Classifiers</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/portfolio/tcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/portfolio/tcc/</guid>
      <description>Gradient Boosting Machines (GBMs) is a supervised machine learning algorithm that has been achieving state-of-the-art results in a wide range of different problems and winning machine learning competitions. When building any machine learning model, the hyperparameter optimization can become a costly and time-consuming task depending on the number and the hyperparameter space of the tuning procedure. Machine learning users that are not experienced researchers or data science professionals can struggle to define which hyperparameters and values to choose when starting the model tuning, especially with newer GBMs implementations like the XGBoost and LightGBM library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women&#39;s Shoes Prices - Kaggle EDA</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/portfolio/shoes-eda/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/portfolio/shoes-eda/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this project is to study the Women&amp;rsquo;s Shoes Prices dataset from Kaggle, which contains a list of women&amp;rsquo;s shoes and the prices they were sold. The data was originally made available at Kaggle by the Datafiniti Company. This project was done mainly to showcase some basic EDA techniques (like histograms and ECDF) but at the same time diving deep into more complicated business questions, e.g. using Fuzzy matching to find out the most popular shoe colors in the dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snacker - AI Recommender System</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/portfolio/snacker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/portfolio/snacker/</guid>
      <description>Snacker is a full-fledged social network for snack lovers all over the world. The website itself was built using the Flask library for the back-end, and the recommendation engine was implemented using a specific collaborative filtering technique called Matrix Factorization. The data was stored using MongoDB for prototyping and testing, more details about the methodology can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movies Ontology - iMDb</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/portfolio/movies-ontology/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/portfolio/movies-ontology/</guid>
      <description>A knowledge-based systems is an area of study in artificial intelligence which tries to capture human knowledge (which usually are experts in the system) and embedded them into rules in a system. In this specific project iMDb data was used to create an ontology of movies, by parsing iMDb datasets and adding them into the ontology. The modelling of the ontology was made with Protégé, an open-source ontology editor, using a Description Logic called the Web Ontology Language (OWL).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating grid/image points in Python</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/2017-09-17-image-grid-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/2017-09-17-image-grid-python/</guid>
      <description>I was doing some assignment about the Percolation Problem, where given a graph, find if the top of the graph is connected to the bottom. There was some test files included, but I wanted to create my own images.
The input file of my assignment has, in the first line, the dimensions of the image. The images are always in a square ratio, n x n &amp;ldquo;pixels&amp;rdquo;. The remaining lines of the file contains pairs (a b) of the coordinates in the grid n x n.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atom &amp; Latex</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/2017-05-24-atom-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/2017-05-24-atom-latex/</guid>
      <description>LaTeX is a DSL (domain specific language) that provides powerful typesetting tools. You can write complex mathematical expressions and much more, for example, the following characteristic polynomial expression was rendered using LaTeX (MathJax):
$$ \chi(\lambda) = \left| \begin{array}{ccc} \lambda - a &amp;amp; -b &amp;amp; -c \\\
-d &amp;amp; \lambda - e &amp;amp; -f \\\
-g &amp;amp; -h &amp;amp; \lambda - i \end{array} \right| $$
There are amazing online software to work with LaTeX such as ShareLaTeX or Overleaf, but sometimes you don&amp;rsquo;t have access to the internet, or want to have a compact environment to do most of your job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atom editor</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/2017-03-21-atom-edit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/2017-03-21-atom-edit/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever heard of Atom? Atom is a text editor, similar to Sublime Text, but with a lot of different features, and much more flexibility and freedom. It&amp;rsquo;s described as A hackable text editor for the 21st century, because it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to create and change many of the settings available, and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot!
Atom is my personal editor, I prefer using it than the proprietary (but relatively good) Sublime Text, and other MAINSTREAM editors like vi/vim or emacs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debug C programs using gdb</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/2017-03-12-debug-gdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/2017-03-12-debug-gdb/</guid>
      <description>GDB(GNU Project Debugger) is, as the name implies, a debugger with a lot of features to make your life easy when programming in C. Using gdb helps to debug C programs in real execution time, i.e. you can put break points in the program to evaluate the value of variables, detect when something has gone wrong, and many other uses. Here I&amp;rsquo;ll cover the basics that I use to debug simple C programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast and easy Python LAN server</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/2017-03-12-python-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/2017-03-12-python-server/</guid>
      <description>This is a very simple tip, but it&amp;rsquo;s very useful when you want others to access your files, or you want to transfer files easily. Just open the terminal, navigate to the folder you want to serve, and then type:
$ python -m SimpleHTTPServer The server will be created in the IP of your machine.
To find your IP, type
$ ifconfig -all or
$ ip a If you&amp;rsquo;re using Python 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debian Stretch setup</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/2017-02-23-debian-stretch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/2017-02-23-debian-stretch/</guid>
      <description>Hello! In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show how is the setup that I use, the most common applications I mostly use when programming, some useful plugins, anyway, my complete programming environment. I&amp;rsquo;ll first cover my OS setup, then the applications and finally the customizations. Feel free to contact me if there&amp;rsquo;s any doubt, but I&amp;rsquo;ll try to be clear and concise.
DISCLAIMER: You do everything in your &amp;gt;OWN&amp;lt; risk! :D
 The setup I use a dualboot with debian and Windows 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2nd website version</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/portfolio/website2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/portfolio/website2/</guid>
      <description>This was my second website, where I used Jekyll to write a few blog posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Law of Large Numbers Simulator</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/portfolio/largenumsim/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/portfolio/largenumsim/</guid>
      <description>This is a project to demonstrate in graph plotting and real data, Weak Law of Large numbers, which is a very useful Theorem used in statistics. As our website says: &amp;quot; In practice, it (the Weak Law of Large Numbers) dictates that, if repeated enough times, the accumulate results of the same experiment will tend to its real mathematical probabilities.&amp;rdquo;
The website plots in real time the graph of throwing a dice or a coin the number of times the user specifies, so it&amp;rsquo;s completely interactive, and the user have fully control over the start number, the amount of throws to perform, and even the speed of the plot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1st website version</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/portfolio/website1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/portfolio/website1/</guid>
      <description>This was my first website. You can check it out for more projects related to my programming work at high school.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>