<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data science on Juliano Garcia</title>
    <link>https://robotenique.github.io/tags/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data science on Juliano Garcia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robotenique.github.io/tags/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Histograms for efficient gradient boosting</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/gbm-histogram/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/gbm-histogram/</guid>
      <description>Gradient Boosting GBM or Gradient Boosting Machines are a form of machine learning algorithms based on additive models. The currently most widely known implementations of it are the XGBoost and LightGBM libraries, and they are common choices for modeling supervised learning problems based on structured data. Generally, the output model in boosting is created by iteratively building weak learners, where each new weak learner weights more the mispredictions of the last learner, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethically Aware Recommender Systems in Social Media</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/ethically-aware-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/ethically-aware-systems/</guid>
      <description>This post is based on an article I wrote some time ago; There may be some inconsistencies with the references, sorry.
Reccomender Systems In a world where digital information is increasing every year, recommender systems are very important tools to handle the challenge of information overload. A recommender system is a type of information filtering system with the ability to filter information from a large amount of data generated dynamically, according to a given preference, observed behavior or interest from the user [1].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving your statistical inferences</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/improving-your-statistical-inferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/improving-your-statistical-inferences/</guid>
      <description>Why study inferential statistics? It&amp;rsquo;s very common to read news and articles with &amp;ldquo;studies have shown that X!&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;science proves that Y&amp;rdquo; in today&amp;rsquo;s age of information. Or even read scientific papers with some dubious affirmations when dealing with reporting results and drawing conclusions from experimental data. Statistical inference is one of those topics in which the basic concepts are very important to grasp to avoid any misconceptions when interpreting it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monte Carlo simulation of a multi-spin roulette mechanic</title>
      <link>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/fortune-cat-simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robotenique.github.io/posts/fortune-cat-simulation/</guid>
      <description>Last year I found out about a Gacha game called Saint Seiya Awakening, which I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to play for some time, but then gave up on it. However I still do watch people play it, people who usually have enough time to invest in the game (it demands quite an amount of your time to be at a competitive level). Gacha games are usually free-to-play, but it is full of loot boxes, roulettes, slot machines, microtransactions and everything else that makes the player want to buy stuff in-game.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>